WEB DEVELOPER

A detail-oriented web developer that utilizes a combination of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery to build appealing, responsive websites. Experienced in CMS platforms, particularly WordPress, and familiar with creating custom themes to meet client needs. Enjoys coding, problem-solving, debugging, and a good podcast.

Experience

OCT 2015 -PRESENT

WEB DEVELOPER

Allegheny Conference on Community Development

- Responsible for the backend and front-end development, maintains and updates company and affiliate websites and intranet.
- Implements and collects google analytics of client sites with related teams to assist with campaigns to increase user traffic.
- Ensures sites are responsive and browser compatible.
- Registers and renews domain names and website hosting.
- Designs with SEO best practices.

JUNE 2014 -OCT 2015

GRAPHIC DESIGN MANAGER

Heartland ECSI

- Managed the digital assets library and additional needs of the marketing communications department.
- Lead the design process for marketing campaigns involving print and newsletters.
- Created company style guide to include branding colors, fonts, and proper use of logo for print and digital needs.

JUNE 2014 -PRESENT

WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance

MBM Contracting

March 2018 - June 2018

Developed a custom WordPress theme for new homepage layout and design. Included additional functions to allow client to add desired content and images to their website as needed. Provided a user guide on new post type features upon completion of project.

Pittsburgh Technical College

June 2016 - July 2017

Assisted with launch of new site by collecting, editing and uploading images to be used on website. Provided consultation services to improve site's layout design and features to increase appeal and user experience to help increase leads for potential new students.

Carnegie Mellon University "Brag Book" March 2015 - April 2015

Worked with in-house web developers and online marketing team to perform website updates and maintenance on CMU's "Brag Book" by adding HTML, JavaScript, CSS as well as editing and preparing images for web display.

Skills & Expertise

SOFTWARE

Adobe Creative Cloud, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, Dreamweaver, Atom, Visual Studio Code, MailChimp, Formstack, Google Analytics

TECHNICAL SPECIALITES

- HTML5
- JavaScript
- CSS3
- jQueryGit
- PHPNodeIS
- Terminal
- WordPress

Education

PITTSBURGH TECHNICAL INSTITUTE, OAKDALE, PA

Associate in Science Degree, Multimedia Technologies

2014 - 2015

Concentration in Web Interactive/Development GPA: 3.92

2007 - 2009

Concentration in Video & 3-Dimensional Design GPA: 3.94

Achievements

- Lead WordPress Meetup on topic of CMB2 plugin
- Serves on Pittsburgh Technical College Multimedia Web Advisory Board
- Featured on "Hallway Chats", a podcast that interviews users within the WordPress community